<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>nathanrw - books</title>
	<link href="https://nathanrw.dev/tags/books/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://nathanrw.dev"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://nathanrw.dev/tags/books/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Spear</title>
		<published>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://nathanrw.dev/posts/20230411-the-spear/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://nathanrw.dev/posts/20230411-the-spear/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;published 1978&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;£1.99, oxfam&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;verdict: mostly good supernatural thriller but also very cursed&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nathanrw.dev&#x2F;posts&#x2F;20230411-the-spear&#x2F;.&#x2F;images&#x2F;the_spear.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the spear front cover&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the good&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;car chase where a mini is pursued by a chieftain tank possessed by the ghost
of Heinrich Himmler&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;final boss is zombie (you guessed it) Heinrich Himmler complete with little
spectacles (they do fall off) aided and abetted by MI5 and elements of the US
military&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zombie&#x27;s head explodes when shot, both removing the head &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; destroying the
brain as per the proper procedure&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the bad&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sustained and very nasty weapons-grade transphobia rears its head toward the
end of the book (there&#x27;s more to be said on violence and misogyny in this book
but this particularly stuck out!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the villain has a prosthetic nose so you know he&#x27;s evil&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the weird&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each chapter begins with an epigraph by Adolf Hitler, Heinrich Himmler,
Richard Wagner or similar, weaving in the story of
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Parsifal&quot;&gt;Parsifal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the Nazis appreciation
of it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elements of the deep state in thrall to a nazi cult are behind the IRA, the
Baader-Meinhof group, the Japanese Red Army, industrial militancy in the
united kingdom (which is in the same category), as well as Palestinian
resistance in a bid to discredit the left and take over the world, in a sort
of proto-QAnon conspiracy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;misc&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protagonist is of the same alcoholic loner template used in the other two
James Herbert books I have read, this time a former arms dealer who used to
work for Mossad, who epitomise a sort of action-hero ethic of righteous
violence meted out against a dehumanised enemy. at the start of the book he
is disillusioned with the cycle of violence and revenge and has quit to work
as a PI. but by the end we&#x27;re perpetrating hate crimes and machine-gunning
nazis so theres a bit of having-your-cake-and-eating-it going on. it&#x27;s a very
violent book and perhaps a bit fascist itself.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
